Madan Baduwal

Kathmandu, Nepal (+9779813120096)

madanbaduwal.github.io

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests lie in Machine Learning, Computer Vision, Pattern Recognition, Multi-Model and Multi-Task Deep Learning, and Cognitive Science for Embodied AI.In particular, I am interested in reverse-engineering the human mind to build embodied machines that can see, listen, speak, learn, and interact with human-level cognition and social intelligence.

EDUCATION

Tribhuvan University, Institute of Engineering

2015 - 2020

Bachelors in Computer Engineering

Kathmandu, Nepal

• Percentage: 72.38%Rank: 2/43

PUBLICATION

1. Prakash Ratna Prajapati, Samiksha Poudel, Madan Baduwal, S., Burlakoti, S., Pandey (Apr. 2021). Signature Verification using Convolutional Neural Network and Autoencoder Journal of the Institute of Engineering ,16, No.1, pp.33-40

INDUSTRY RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

BP Eye Foundation

May 2022 - Ongoing

Sr. Machine Learning & Computer Vision Engineer

Kathmandu, Nepal

• Research on semantic-segmentation and detection algorithm for otitis media based on otoscopy images of the tympanic membrane with an accuracy of 85%. Deployed it as a scalable ML SAAS product on the Dell EMC server by collaborating with multidisciplinary teams.

Fusemachines

Feb 2020 - Feb 2022

Headquater: New York, USA

Machine Learning Engineer

- Led a team of engineers to develop an AI-enabled education platform: fuseclassroom.com. Currently, this platform is running around 60 colleges in Nepal, 20k students are already engaged in this platform.
- Worked on several client-based ML projects from the US as well as internal ML projects of the company in the field of Machine learning. Worked on the whole **Machine Learning pipeline**.
- Involved in in-house training, workshops, math knowledge sharing session, and paper reading sessions on Deep Learning.
- Involved in research, design, review, and refinement of content reading material, quizzes, assignments, and projects for Fusemachines AI Education Programs - "Micro Degree in Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Computer Vision, Natural Language Processing"

National Innovation Center

Jan 2021 - Dec 2021

Computer Vision Engineer(R and D)

Kathmandu, Nepal

- Collaborated with mechanical, electrical, and electronic hardware teams for the deployment of computer vision tasks in robots to create initial prototypes for waiter and service **robots** within **9** months.
- Run simulation tests on docker and Gazebo, Integrated and deployed computer vision tasks in robots with Edge **Devices** like Tensor Processing Units and Jetson Nano, RaspberryPI.
- Created few rule base algorithms from scratch to handling the motion and manipulation for the robot.
- Worked on several computer vision tasks: classification, Localization, Segmentation, Object Detection, Object Tracking, and Face Recognition. Worked on the whole computer vision pipeline.

Omnibluetech

Aug 2019 — Feb 2020

 $Software\ Engineering(INT)$

Kathmandu, Nepal

- Worked on data structured and algorithms, and different structured and unstructured database systems.
- Worked on designing and developing web applications using Front-end technology HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, and backend technology Flask, Django, and WordPress.

WMC Global | Python3,Scikit-learn,Git,AWS

jun 2021 - Dec 2021

• Classify websites into phishing and non-phishing using clustering algorithms for GoDaddy, Bitly, InfoBip, and ICANN under WMC global. Transformed unstructured data into structured data format using rgex.

Student Status Engine | Python3, Snowflake, Scikit-learn, Git, AWS

January 2021 - june 2021

- Created **feature extractor pipeline** that automatically extracts features from the data warehouse(eg: snowflake). Applied machine learning algorithms on extracted features to classify student status into different classes.
- Collaborated with back-end, front-end, and DevOps engineers to test and **deployed model into large-scale production.**

$AI-Robot \mid Python3, TensorFlow 2.0, ROS, Gazebo, TPU, J. nano, R. Pi$

Jan 2021 - Sep 2021

- Retrain a classification model for Edge TPU using post-training quantization(23fps,85% mAP score with pre-training), face recognition using python face recognization library, depth calculation using real sense depth camera, Centroid based object tracking, and write rule base algorithm from scratch.
- Integrated and tested computer vision tasks into ROS, gazebo simulation environment and **implemented it into** waiter and service robot. Visualize robot sensors data into rviz.

Text Extractor | Jupyter Notebook, Python 3, Open CV

July 2019 - October 2020

- Research and experiment on building image preprocessing techniques like erosion and dilation.
- Build a Framework that uses google tesseract and regex to extract information from the form (eg: buyer name, seller name, etc.).

Hastakshar | Python3, OpenCV, Keras, Django

2018-2019

- Research and experiment on Image Localization to improve classifier model using NumPy and OpenCV library.
- Built signature verification CNN classifier system using Tensorflow. Developed Django web interfaces in local machine.

Android apps, Websites, and Packages | C#, Unity, Python 3, HTML, CSS

2015 - 2019

- Android apps: Asteroid Smash, Antigravity Ball, Saveme, Beat Creator
- Web apps: horizonglobal.edu.np,youthcareer.edu.np
- Pypi package: pip install madan

ACHIEVEMENTS AND AWARDS

Tribhuvan University Merit-based scholarship

2015-2019

• Awarded for securing the highest GPA in the Computer Engineering cohort in the 1rd, 2th and 4th semesters respectively. The scholarship was worth \$ 1000 each semester.

Best Idea Winner January 2017

• Best idea winner of the Exhibition organized by Kantipur engineering college and sponsored by Neosphere. Neosphere offered 6 month Ethical Hacking course, which was nearly worth \$ 200

Hackathon Runner-up March 2018

• 1st runner-up of hackathon organizes by Kathmandu University, kavre. The prize was worth \$100.

Best Logic Code July 2019

• Best Logic Code winner organized by Sagarmatha engineering college. The prize was worth \$60.

COURSES COMPLETED AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Certified Ethical Hacking(CEH)-Neosphere
- Neural Networks and Deep Learning-Coursera
- Sequence Model-Coursera
- Effective Client Communication-Fusemachines

EXTRA ACTIVITIES

- Lite Exhibition Participant, Kantipur Engineering College, 2015,2016,2017,2018
- Himalaya Exhibition (HEx) Participant, Himalay College of Engineering, 2017
- Al Workshop Participant , M
Percept Technology Pvt , 2019
- Data Science Workshop Participant, F1Soft International Pvt. Ltd., 2019

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python3, C,C++,Android, HTML/CSS, SQL,PostgreSQL, MySQL

Tools: Scipy, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Scikit-learn, Tensorflow, Opency, NLTK, Jupyter Notebook, Conda

Familiar: Tableau, Latex, Linux, Mongodb, Git, Github, Docker, Django/MVT, Flask, Mlflow, Robot Operating

System(ROS), Raspberry pi, Coral TPU, Unity game engine, Networking, SEO, Wordpress